iarc.fr 2018-11-26

# Privacy policy

Your privacy on the Internet is of utmost importance to the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC), a specialized agency of the World Health Organization (WHO). This privacy statement describes IARC's policy concerning the gathering and sharing of visitors' information through the IARC website. It applies to all "IARC sites" - that is, all sites within the "iarc.fr" domain name.

### What information does IARC collect?

##### Normal website usage

In general, you can browse the IARC site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. The only information we gather during general browsing is from standard server logs. These include your IP (Internet Protocol) address, domain name, browser type, operating system, and information such as the website that referred you to us, the files you download, the pages you visit, and the dates/times of those visits.

##### Collection of personally identifiable information

If you register for a newsletter, log on to certain IARC sites, order a book, request information, provide feedback, apply for a job, join a discussion group, or join an electronic mailing list, you will be asked to provide personal information such as your name, postal address, and email address.

This information is collected only with your knowledge and permission, and is kept in various IARC databases and mailing lists. If you are purchasing ebooks using the web, you may be asked to provide your credit card details. These details are transferred to a secure, online payment service, hosted outside IARC. Credit card information is not retained by IARC. However, ebook sales transacted through third-party services are subject to service providers′ own policies. Cardholder data may be transferred, processed, and stored outside of EU Member States, and as set forth in the [payment service provider′s Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/fr/privacy), may be subject to disclosure as required by applicable law. IARC is not responsible for the privacy policies or content of third-party sites.

IARC sites with specific requirements to collect personal information may publish a privacy policy specific for that site. In these cases, the site-specific policies will be complementary to this general IARC privacy policy but will give additional details for that particular site.

For certain IARC sites, registering or supplying personal information sets a cookie*. By setting this cookie, IARC will remember your details the next time you visit, so you don′t have to re-enter the information. This helps us to provide you with a better service.

Joining electronic discussion groups may mean that other participants of the discussion group (including non-IARC employees) will see personal information that you have volunteered. For open discussion groups, this information will be public.

### What does IARC do with the information it collects?

##### Normal website usage

The information gathered during general browsing of the “iarc.fr” domain is used to analyse trends and usage of the IARC site and to improve the usefulness of the site. It is not connected with any personal information.

##### Personally identifiable information

IARC may use the personal information you provide to:  

  * Contact you – either in response to a query or suggestion, or to mail newsletters, documents, publications, etc. to you;
  * Manage and process your job application;
  * Confirm your purchases and registrations on the site;
  * Obtain payment for purchases through the site (via credit card);
  * Remember your online profile and preferences;
  * Help you quickly find information that is relevant to you based on your interests, and help us create site content most relevant to you;
  * Perform statistical analysis.

### What if I don′t want to provide personal information?

Providing personal information on the IARC site is optional. If you choose not to provide personal information, you can still browse and use the IARC site, but you will not be able to carry out certain actions such as purchase items, register for a newsletter, or apply for a job.

### Opting out and changing your information

At any time, you can cancel or modify your information by returning to the webpage where you first provided the information and contacting the focal point for that page/IARC department. Where contact details are not provided on the page, you can refer to [this page](http://www.iarc.fr/en/contact-us/index.php) for further information.

### Security

We do not sell or share any personally identifiable information volunteered on the IARC site to any third party. Any information provided to IARC by users of the IARC site is held with the utmost care and security and will not be used in ways other than as set forth in this privacy policy, or in any site-specific policies, or in ways to which you have explicitly consented. IARC uses a range of technologies and security measures to protect the information maintained on our systems from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

All our employees who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of official business matters, including personal data.

The IARC site contains links to sites external to the ”iarc.fr” domain. IARC is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such sites.

### Notification of changes

Changes to this privacy policy will be posted on the IARC homepage at [www.iarc.fr](http://www.iarc.fr/).

### Contact

For questions or queries regarding this privacy policy, please contact us at [com@iarc.fr](mailto:com@iarc.fr).

***** Cookies  
A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent from a web server to your browser. It is normally used to assign a unique identification to your computer and securely store information such as user IDs, passwords, preferences, and online profiles. 

It is stored on the hard drive of your computer. You can choose not to have cookies delivered by IARC sites by changing your browser settings. Different websites can send their own cookies to your computer. To protect your privacy, your browser only allows a website to access the cookies it has already sent you, not the cookies sent by other sites.
